# **Ekta Singh**

# Web/Java Developer

Phone no: +91-8882496289 | E-mail: mailto:ektasingh151@gmail.com

#### PROFILE SUMMARY

Diligent Software Engineer and OCJP certified (93%) java professional with 3.4 years of experience. Eager to join the organization to bring in topclass Java development and problem-solving skills. In previous roles consistently received high user experience scores for all web development projects and certificate of appreciation for successful implementation.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Developer - Make My Trip (Ind.) Pvt. Ltd. /Tek Systems

Nov 2019 - Mar 2020

Gurgaon, Haryana

- Implemented suppliers priority ordering logic for hotel attributes stated by different suppliers of MMT Group using java, node.js & react.js.
- Designed contract for catering additional data and restructuring present data coming from different suppliers of MMT.

# Software Developer - Nucleus Software Exports Ltd.

Jan. 2018 - Sep 2019

Noida, U.P.

- Achieved successful implementation of Internal Fund Transfer (IFT) payment module of FinnAxia for a tier-1 bank of Kenya using REST API.
- Developed Head Office branch API & completed the implementation & unit testing of Cheque Book Request API for a tier-1 South African bank.
- Succeeded in the implementation of Nigeria Instant Payment (NIP) for a tier-1 South African bank.
- Developed 'Customer User Authentication Rights' requirement for Business Internet Banking (BIB) portal of a tier-1 Malaysian bank; following best practices and received a **Certificate of Appreciation** for my efforts.

# Java Developer – Innverse Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

July 2016 - Dec 2017

Noida, U.P.

- Developed service interfaces for a USA based building and construction company.
- Successfully implemented partial-shipment and invoice generation process for an online inventory management system.

#### Summer Intern - HCL Infosystems Ltd.

June 2013 - July 2013

Noida, U.P.

• Selected for 45 days internship program and developed a minor java-based application 'Jaipur Bus Info' with MySQL as database layer.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

• An Oracle Certified Java Programmer (OCJP-6) certified programmer. Secured 93% marks.

September 2015

# **EDUCATION**

# Global Institute of Technology, Jaipur - BTech - Computer Science & Engineering (CSE)

July 2010 - Aug 2014

- Bachelor of technology in Computer Science & Engineering. Obtained a CGPA of 6.5.
- Followed my passion in java-based development and served as a helping hand for my Prof. in small scale web projects and work flow.

### SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

Programming languages: Expertise in Core Java, Spring IOC, Spring MVC, Spring AOP, Spring Security;

Intermediary skills in Data Structures, Hibernate, MySQL, JavaScript **Software Packages:** Eclipse, STS, Web container, Application server, Git

Soft Skills: Perseverance, Critical thinking, Work ethic, Adaptability, Fluent communication

#### **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

- Regular participation in 'Knowledge Sharing Sessions' held every Friday in Nucleus Software to share technical knowledge.
- Regular attendee of NucTech society meetups; a tech. society and Learning Resource Center; a book club society in Nucleus Software.